MAËL BOCCARDI

Quantitative Analyst | Data Science

EXPERIENCE

Quantitative Analyst - NATIXIS INVESTMENT MANAGERS

m Sep 2022 - Oct 2023

Paris

- Apprenticeship with Mr Olivier Roussel focusing on tools and portfolio constructions, with emphasis on Risk Parity funds.
- Research in systematic allocation based on economic regimes.
- Backtesting for retirement fund allocation & performance attribution.
- Worked on technical indicators & option strategies' greek calculation.

Trader Assistant Intern - AQUAE CAPITAL

🛗 July 2022 - Sep 2022

Marseille

- Internship with Mr Richard Schoeb, focusing on updated performance data & indicator construction.
- Built a risk alert model based on market context and asset behavior.
- Used data visualization to enhance trading strategy comprehension.
- Gained insight into equity portfolio risk management and options hedging.

Quantitative Research Intern - Aix-Marseille School of Economics

May 2022 - Jun 2023

Marseille

- Conducted a comprehensive study on asset class volatility inter-dependencies, manipulating and analyzing data using R Studio.
- Utilized GARCH models to calculate and extract volatility from factors to developed an error-correction model to express long & short-run volatility relationships.

EDUCATION

Chartered Financial Analyst - Paris Dauphine University

2024

Paris

• Fixed Income, Economics, Portfolio Management, and Derivative.

Magistère Economist Engineer - Master Quantitative Finance - Aix-Marseille School of Economics - Centrale Méditerranée

2023

Marseille

 Dual Degree with Honors in Computer Science, Big Data, Market Finance, Econometrics, Macro/Microeconomics, Time Serie Econometrics, Stochastic Mathematics, and Risk Management.

Master of Science - University of Kent (exchange semester)

∰ 2022

♥ Canterbury

• Focus on Financial Economics, CAPM & Factor models, Econometric Methods, Macroeconomics, and Microeconomics.

Bachelor of Economics & Finance - Faculty of Economy and Management

₩ 2021

Marseille

 Honors in Mathematics & Probability, Econometrics, Macro/Microeconomics, Financial Accounting, Risk & Uncertainty, Fx Derivatives, and Computer Science.

- +33619872950
- @ mael.boccardi@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/maël-boccardi/
- % https://mtbcd.github.io/Portfolio-Website/

ABOUT ME

With experience as a Quantitative Analyst at Natixis Investment Managers, I specialize in Python-based financial models. I possess skills in econometrics, risk management, and portfolio construction, backed by a Master's in quantitative finance and current CFA studies at Université Paris Dauphine. I'm passionate about applying my data science expertise to complex financial challenges.

SKILLS

Quantitative Analysis	Data Science
Financial Modeling	Risk Management
Python R SQL	Econometrics
Machine Learning English	
Portfolio Construction French	

PROJECTS

- Air traffic prediction
- Utilize predictive modeling techniques, including Prophet, RNNs, LSTM, and XGBoost, to analyze and forecast air traffic data. Leverage the Streamlit interface for dynamic data visualization.
- Regression Analysis and Data Visualization
- Investigates the intricate dynamics between gold and cryptocurrency, using GARCH model for volatility estimation, ARDL for impact assessment, and VAR models.
- Programming for Portfolio Construction
- Developed programs for various portfolio constructions: Min-Var, Eq-Weighted, Mean-Var, Risk Parity, HRP.
- Master's Thesis on Regime-Based Dynamic Allocation Approach
- Focused on developing a multi-factor (CAPM, AQR) portfolio optimization method that adapts its allocation based on macroeconomic conditions.

INTERESTS

- Sport (athleticism, climbing, snorkeling, skateboard)
- Reading & Poetry
- Travels (Asia, North America, Europe)